Guide to the Harold C. Geyer papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harold C. Geyer papers
1941-1989
1941-1949
MS 1726
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The papers consist of the original manuscripts, drawings and etchings, as well as published copies of All Men Have Loved Thee: A Song of France and The Long Way Home: A Song of France. Also included are book reviews of the publications; programs for lectures and slide presentations given by Geyer; and Ombres et Lumières de Troyes, which contains reproductions of Geyer's previously published etchings.
Geyer, Harold C.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harold C. Geyer, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Harold C. Geyer was born in Cold Springs, New York, in 1905. He received a B.A. (1926) and a B.F.A. (1930) from Yale University. In 1933 he travelled to France to study medieval architecture, remaining until 1934. The result of this sojourn was the publication of All Men Have Loved Thee: A Song of France (1941) and The Long Way Home: A Song of France (1949), both written and illustrated by him. The first of these autobiographical works focuses on the political and social unrest in France from 1933 to 1934 through the use of letters and drawings of an art student, and reproductions of Parisian newspaper stories. The second work, similar in format, continues up to the war, plus delves into the author's love of France, its history and architecture.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of the original manuscripts, drawings and etchings, as well as published copies of All Men Have Loved Thee: A Song of France and The Long Way Home: A Song of France. Also included are book reviews of the publications; programs for lectures and slide presentations given by Geyer; and Ombres et Lumières de Troyes, which contains reproductions of Geyer's previously published etchings.
Architecture, Gothic; Drawing; Etching; France -- History; France -- Politics and government -- 1914-1940; Troyes (France); Geyer, Harold C.
- Original accession
  - Correspondence, 1941, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interviews/book reviews, 1941-1942, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lecture/slide presentations [programs], 1940s, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - All Men Have Loved Thee: A Song of France, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Long Way Home: A Song of France, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ombres et Lumieres de Troyes [contains illustrations by Harold C. Geyer], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - All Men Have Loved Thee: A Song of France [original manuscripts with etchings (2 volumes); pen and ink drawings, 1941 (Box 2)
  - The Long Way Home: A Song of France [etchings (1 volume) and loose materials], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Oversize (Box 4, Folder 93)